WeiQin Chuah

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/weiqin Github: github.com/weiqin

Webpage: https://waychin-weiqin.github.io/

ABOUT ME

I am a self-motivated and enthusiastic Ph.D. graduate in the School of Engineering (Mechanical, Manufacturing, and Mechatronics) from RMIT University, Australia. I am currently working as a post-doctoral researcher at the same institution, where I conduct cutting-edge research in geometric computer vision, generalizable deep learning, and representation learning. My research interests span machine learning, computer vision, autonomous navigation, and robotics. The developed systems will be highly beneficial for real-life applications such as autonomous driving, robotics, augmented reality, and more.

Email: weiqin5645@gmail.com

Mobile: +61 424 095 691

Professional Experience

RMIT University / Ford Motor Company Melbourne, Australia Research Assistant (Deep Learning, Computer Vision) Oct 2022 - Current Research and development of an intelligent and automated visual inspection system for self-piercing rivets. RMIT University / Bondi Labs Melbourne, Australia Casual Researcher (Deep Learning, Computer Vision) Sept 2022 - Oct 2022 Research and development of an intelligent and automated visual inspection system for vet-assistive technology. RMIT University Melbourne, Australia Mechatronics Engineering Intern (Machine Learning, Image Processing, Sensor Fusion) Dec 2017 - Feb 2018 Research and development of an intelligent cow screening and cleaning system Melbourne, Australia Mechanical Engineer Intern (Mechanical Design) Apr 2017 - Oct 2017 Research and development of a 6 degree of freedom assistant robotic arm, Jeva

Publications

An Information-Theoretic Method to Automatic Shortcut Avoidance and Domain Generalization for Dense Prediction Tasks

IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (T-PAMI) 2023 WQ Chuah, R Tennakoon, R Hoseinnezhad, A Bab-Hadiashar, D Suter

• Towards Building a Vet-Assist System: Animal pose estimation and counting walking steps Australasian Conference on Robotics and Automation (ACRA) 2022

WQ Chuah, A Bab-Hadiashar, R Tennakoon, F Zambetta, R Hoseinnezhad, J Hall, J Marshall, S Smith, M Stevenson

• ITSA: An Information-Theoretic Approach to Automatic Shortcut Avoidance and Domain Generalization in Stereo Matching Networks

IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) 2022 WQ Chuah, R Tennakoon, R Hoseinnezhad, A Bab-Hadiashar, D Suter

• Semantic Guided Long Range Stereo Depth Estimation for Safer Autonomous Vehicle Applications IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Transportation Systems (T-ITS) 2022 WQ Chuah, R Tennakoon, R Hoseinnezhad, D Suter, A Bab-Hadiashar

• Deep Learning-Based Incorporation of Planar Constraints for Robust Stereo Depth Estimation in **Autonomous Vehicle Applications**

IEEE Transactions on Itelligent Transportation Systems (T-ITS) 2021

WQ Chuah, R Tennakoon, R Hoseinnezhad, A Bab-Hadiashar

Machine Vision-Enabled Traffic Controller for Safer and Smoother Traffic Flow Around Construction Sites IEEE Intelligent Transportation Systems Conference (ITSC) 2019 WQ Chuah, R Tennakoon, R Hoseinnezhad, A Bab-Hadiashar

• State Transition for Statistical SLAM Using Planar Features in 3D Point Clouds Sensors, Volume 19, Issue 1614, 2019

AK Gostar, C Fu, WQ Chuah, MI Hossain, R Tennakoon, A Bab-Hadiashar, R Hoseinnezhad

Teaching Experience

Post-graduate

Computational Machine Learning

RMIT University Tutor / Lab Demonstrator 2021 - 2022

RMIT University Deep Learning Tutor / Lab Demonstrator Semester 2 2022

Under-graduate

Machine Learning RMIT University Tutor / Lab Demonstrator 2021 - 2022

RMIT University **Digital Fundamentals** Lab Demonstrator Semester 1 2021

Mechatronics Principle RMIT University Teaching Assistant Semester 1 2020

EDUCATION

Royal Melbourne Institute of Technology (RMIT) Melbourne, Australia PhD (School of Engineering) Feb 2019 - Oct 2022

Thesis: Passive visual depth estimation in the deep learning era.

Royal Melbourne Institute of Technology (RMIT) Melbourne, Australia BSc (Engineering), Adv. Manufacturing and Mechatronics (First Class Honours) Mar 2014 - Nov 2018

Projects

RMIT University Melbourne, Australia Wide Baseline Stereo Data Collection (Data acquisition, System Integration) May 2019 - April 2020

RMIT University Melbourne, Australia Mechatronics Final Year Projects (Computer Vision, Robotics) Mar 2017 - Oct 2018

Development of Statistical SLAM Using Planar Features in 3D Point Clouds

Real-time driving imageries data collection using multiple cameras, LiDAR and GPS sensor.

SKILLS SUMMARY

• Languages: Python, C++, MATLAB, Bash

• Frameworks: Pandas, Scikit, OpenCV, TensorFlow, Keras, PyTorch • Tools/Software: Docker, GIT, Jupyter, Carla, CATIA, Solidworks Linux, Windows, macOS, Arduino, AWS • Platforms:

Extracurricular Experience

High Powered Rocket Team - HIVE RMIT

Jun 2018 - Mar 2019

Recovery Systems Team Leader

Develop a reliable rocket recovery system to allow sufficient drag and counteract the force of gravity for minimizing the landing impact. Our team won the first place in the Australian Universities Rocket Competition in the 30,000ft category in 2019.

RMIT Mates Program Feb 2016 - Oct 2016

Volunteer Mentor

Provide practical advice, social interaction and general academic guidance to newly-arrived international, regional or rural/remote students in their first semester of study at RMIT University.

RMIT Student Learning Advisor Mentors (SLAMs)

Mar 2016 - Jul 2016

Provide academic advice and share strategies with students on time management and study planning to achieve outstanding results.

Referees

Available upon request.

Volunteer Mentor